<output>
<conclusion>
The tested additive perturbation F16 = F15 + 0.1·χ_3 did not measurably shift the spectral signature toward the known violator region: its pc1_complex remained 0.9412 (vs 0.9413 for F15), far above the violator threshold of 0.92.
</conclusion>
<methods>
I followed a from-scratch reconstruction workflow in Python using numpy, pandas, scipy, matplotlib, numba, mpmath, and cypari2. First, I loaded the reference feature table peaks_features_F1_F12_normalized_full_with_spectral_complex.csv and summarized its class-level spectral coordinates. I then installed/imported cypari2 and used PARI/GP to generate the Ramanujan Delta coefficients τ(n) up to N=10^6 via mfDelta()/mfcoefs. These were analytically normalized as a_n = τ(n)/n^(11/2). I defined the quartic primitive character mod 5 by χ_5(1)=1, χ_5(2)=i, χ_5(3)=-i, χ_5(4)=-1, χ_5(5m)=0, and constructed F15 coefficients b_n = a_n·χ_5(n). I defined the real primitive character mod 3 by χ_3(n)=0 for 3|n, χ_3(n)=1 for n≡1 mod 3, and χ_3(n)=-1 for n≡2 mod 3, then formed F16 coefficients c_n = b_n + 0.1·χ_3(n). Next, I computed ω(n), the number of distinct prime factors, for all n≤10^6, and stratified the weighted main-sum coefficients by k=ω(n)∈{0,…,7}. Peak finding was performed over t∈[10^4,2×10^4] using the same main-sum framework described in the project context: S(t)=Σ_{n≤N} a_n n^(-1/2-it), evaluated with Numba-jitted complex summation and local refinement. A coarse scan used N_short=10^5 on a grid with spacing 0.05, local maxima were detected with scipy.signal.find_peaks, then all coarse candidates were rescored with the full N=10^6 sum. The top candidates were refined in two stages (±0.05 with 21 points, then ±0.005 with 41 points) to obtain the 200 largest peaks for each function. At those peaks I computed the complex ω-stratified sums S_k(t), k=0,…,7. I then formed the 8×8 real symmetric matrix M_jk = E[Re(S_j·conj(S_k))] across the 200 peaks, computed its eigenvalues with numpy.linalg.eigvalsh, defined pc1_complex as λ_1 / Σ_i λ_i, and defined H_complex as the Shannon entropy -Σ_i p_i log p_i with p_i = λ_i / Σ_j λ_j. To quantify stability, I also ran a 500-resample bootstrap over peaks for F15 and F16. Finally, I created a summary plot overlaying the reference class coordinates with the newly computed F15 and F16 positions and saved intermediate artifacts to disk.
</methods>
<results>
The reference spectral coordinates from peaks_features_F1_F12_normalized_full_with_spectral_complex.csv showed known violators clustered near pc1_complex≈0.903 and H_complex≈0.19–0.21, while GRH-true reference classes occupied pc1_complex≈0.937–0.965 and H_complex≈0.09–0.13. Specifically, the reference violator centroid across F4, F5p, F5m, and F12 was (pc1_complex, H_complex) = (0.90396, 0.20130). The recomputed F15 function had pc1_complex = 0.94127 and H_complex = 0.25767 from its 8×8 M_jk matrix, with eigenvalues [34.0014, 1.7832, 0.2073, 0.1025, 0.0255, 0.0031, 9.0×10^-6, 0]. The perturbed function F16 had pc1_complex = 0.94122 and H_complex = 0.26190, with eigenvalues [34.1395, 1.7301, 0.2541, 0.1122, 0.0317, 0.0038, 1.18×10^-5, 0]. The direct shift from F15 to F16 was therefore Δpc1_complex = -0.00005 and ΔH_complex = +0.00424. Bootstrap uncertainty estimates over the 200-peak sets were: F15 pc1_complex SD = 0.00455 and H_complex SD = 0.01459; F16 pc1_complex SD = 0.00440 and H_complex SD = 0.01422. The observed shift was negligible relative to these uncertainties (Δpc1/SD≈-0.01; ΔH/SD≈0.29). In pc1_complex alone, both F15 and F16 remained about 0.037 above the violator centroid and both remained well above the stated violator threshold pc1_complex<0.92. The top-peak magnitudes were similar for both functions: max |S| = 18.3143 for F15 and 18.3097 for F16. Output files saved were peaks_F15_F16_complex.csv, F15_F16_spectral.npz, and F15_F16_spectral_position.png.
</results>
<challenges>
The main challenge was that the workspace did not contain precomputed F15/F16 coefficient or S_k arrays, so the full coefficient-generation and spectral pipeline had to be rebuilt from scratch. cypari2 was initially unavailable and had to be installed before PARI/GP coefficient generation could proceed. Another important limitation is range confounding: the reference table mostly uses peaks from substantially higher t ranges than the requested interval [10^4, 2×10^4], and prior project notes explicitly warn that spectral features depend on the t-range. Therefore, cross-comparison of the absolute F15/F16 coordinates to the historical reference cloud must be treated cautiously; the within-range comparison between F15 and F16 is the more reliable result. A second methodological caveat is that I used the quartic primitive character mod 5 consistent with the project’s χ_5 convention, but I could not directly verify the exact r62 implementation from a stored source file in this workspace. Finally, the entropy scale used in the reference file could not be independently revalidated from stored complex reference S_k arrays, so the strongest and most reliable conclusion comes from the pc1_complex comparison and the within-analysis F15→F16 shift rather than absolute entropy matching.
</challenges>
<discussion>
Within a fully range-matched analysis, adding a small non-automorphic term 0.1·L(s,χ_3) to the GRH-true twisted modular L-function F15 did not induce a meaningful move toward the known violator signature. This argues against the hypothesis, at least for this perturbation size and this t-range, and suggests that the previously observed violator cluster is not triggered by a small additive admixture of this particular Dirichlet component. Instead, the signature appears more robust to weak additive contamination than hypothesized, or alternatively may require either a larger perturbation, a different non-automorphic component, or a different peak regime to become visible. Because prior project findings indicate strong conditioning effects at peaks and strong t-range confounding, this null result should be interpreted specifically as a controlled, range-matched negative result rather than a universal impossibility statement. Scientifically, the result is consistent with the idea that the spectral violator signature may depend on more substantial structural departures from automorphic multiplicativity than a 10% additive χ_3 term provides.
</discussion>
<proposed-next-hypotheses>
A larger additive perturbation c·L(s,χ_3) with c≥0.3 will produce a detectable monotonic decrease in pc1_complex for the F15+c·L(s,χ_3) family under the same range-matched protocol. Another testable hypothesis is that additive perturbations by non-automorphic components derived from Davenport–Heilbronn-type constructions will move F15 toward the violator cluster more strongly than perturbations by the primitive Dirichlet character χ_3.
</proposed-next-hypotheses>
<artifacts>
<artifact>
<file-name>peaks_F15_F16_complex.csv</file-name>
<artifact-type>agent_produced</artifact-type>
<artifact-description>CSV table containing the 200 refined peak locations for F15 and F16 in t∈[10^4, 2×10^4], their total peak magnitudes, and the complex ω-stratified sums S_k recorded as real and imaginary parts for k=0,…,7. It was generated from the reconstructed N=10^6 main-sum pipeline using Numba-accelerated evaluation.</artifact-description>
</artifact>
<artifact>
<file-name>F15_F16_spectral.npz</file-name>
<artifact-type>agent_produced</artifact-type>
<artifact-description>NumPy archive containing the F15 and F16 8×8 spectral matrices M_jk, their eigenvalues, scalar spectral features, and peak locations. It was created from the 200-peak ω-stratified complex sums computed in this analysis.</artifact-description>
</artifact>
<artifact>
<file-name>peaks_features_F1_F12_normalized_full_with_spectral_complex.csv</file-name>
<artifact-type>external_source</artifact-type>
<artifact-description>Reference feature table already present in the workspace, containing 2200 peaks from the historical F1–F12 analysis with class-level spectral coordinates pc1_complex, H_complex, pc1_mag, and H_mag. It was used as the comparison feature space for positioning F15 and F16.</artifact-description>
</artifact>
</artifacts>
</output>
