<output>
<conclusion>
Using a transparent substitute feature set built from peak-local statistics, the SVM still achieved essentially perfect temporal-split discrimination between F1 (ζ) and F4 (L_DH), with temporal-split AUC = 1.000 and bootstrap 95% CI = [0.9996, 1.0000], so the hypothesis that honest validation would reduce AUC but keep it high (>0.95) was supported only partially because AUC did not drop.
</conclusion>
<methods>
I first audited the provided workspace and confirmed that the only supplied primary document was the 4-page PDF ` v6 — Binding Context Document.pdf`; the accompanying `_v6_prompt.md` file referenced by the PDF was absent. I extracted the PDF contents and verified the function-class table, the statistical reporting requirements (AUC, bootstrap CI, confusion matrix), and the anti-pattern stating that `M_coh = 1/R_comp`. I also confirmed that the precise definitions of the requested features `R_comp`, `M_coh`, and `CAS` were not present anywhere in the workspace. Because the specified feature formulas were missing, I could not faithfully implement the exact Step 0.6 feature set. To avoid fabricating undefined quantities, I used a clearly labeled substitute 3-feature peak-local representation: (1) `A = log|F(1/2+it*)|` at a detected peak `t*`, (2) `B`, the local peak curvature computed from second finite differences of `log|F|` using a spacing proportional to the local mean zero spacing `2π/log t`, and (3) `C`, the local roughness defined as the standard deviation of `log|F|` over a 7-point neighborhood around the peak. These were used as operational substitutes for the missing feature triplet. For F1, I evaluated `|ζ(1/2+it)|` using a fast vectorized Riemann–Siegel implementation with the leading remainder term. For F4, I re-derived the validated Davenport–Heilbronn constant `κ = (sqrt(10 - 2*sqrt(5)) - 2)/(sqrt(5)-1) ≈ 0.2840790438404123` and represented the Davenport–Heilbronn function both as a periodic Dirichlet series and as a linear combination of primitive Dirichlet L-functions mod 5. I validated the `κ` choice by checking that the canonical off-line zero near `s ≈ 0.808517 + 85.69934 i` gave `|L_DH(s)| ≈ 1.07×10^-5`, which is consistent with the literature zero being only approximate. For efficient large-scale scanning, I implemented a fast approximate functional-equation / Riemann–Siegel style evaluator for `L_DH(1/2+it)`, then numerically sanity-checked it against `mpmath.dirichlet` at several candidate peak locations, finding magnitude agreement typically within about 0.1%–1.5% and at worst about 2% for the checked peaks. Because exact evaluation of `L_DH` on the originally requested range `[10^6, 10^7]` was computationally infeasible within the runtime budget using only locally implemented high-accuracy methods, I used a reduced temporal split for the actual classifier experiment: training peaks from `t in [10^3, 10^4]` and testing peaks from `t in [10^4, 10^5]`. I scanned each range on a grid with step size `0.05`, identified local maxima of `|F(1/2+it)|`, and selected the top 50 peaks for each function in each range, giving 50 ζ peaks and 50 L_DH peaks per split. This produced 100 training samples and 100 test samples. I standardized features with `sklearn.preprocessing.StandardScaler`, trained an RBF-kernel SVM (`sklearn.svm.SVC`, `C=1.0`, `gamma='scale'`) on the training set, and evaluated on the held-out temporal test set using AUC and a confusion matrix. For bootstrap uncertainty, I used two nonparametric bootstrap procedures with 1000 iterations each: (1) resampling the held-out test predictions with replacement and recomputing AUC, and (2) resampling the training set with replacement, retraining the SVM each time, and evaluating the resulting model on the same held-out temporal test set. I reported percentile 95% confidence intervals from the bootstrap distributions. All analysis was performed in Python using `numpy`, `mpmath`, `scipy`, `pandas`, `scikit-learn`, and `matplotlib`. I saved the derived peak-feature table as `peaks_features_F1_F4.csv`, the bootstrap AUC arrays as `bootstrap_aucs.npz`, and a final summary figure as `svm_validation_summary.png` and `svm_validation_summary.pdf`.
</methods>
<results>
The workspace audit found no definitions for `R_comp`, `M_coh`, or `CAS`, so the exact requested feature set could not be generated from the provided materials. The only explicit relation available was the anti-pattern note that `M_coh = 1/R_comp`. I therefore used the substitute peak-local features `(A, B, C)` described above. For the Davenport–Heilbronn function, the validated constant was `κ ≈ 0.2840790438404123`. Evaluated at the standard approximate off-line zero `s ≈ 0.808517 + 85.69934 i`, the function value was `L_DH(s) ≈ -2.27×10^-6 - 1.04×10^-5 i`, with magnitude `|L_DH(s)| ≈ 1.07×10^-5`, supporting that the implemented `κ` is numerically consistent with the canonical off-line-zero data. Peak extraction yielded 50 peaks each for ζ and L_DH in the training range `[10^3, 10^4]` and 50 peaks each in the test range `[10^4, 10^5]`, for a total of 200 observations. The approximate ranges of selected peak locations were: ζ train `t ≈ 2448–9826`, L_DH train `t ≈ 3030–9955`, ζ test `t ≈ 30775–99703`, and L_DH test `t ≈ 33804–99973`. Feature means showed systematic separation. In the training split, the mean values were: ζ: `A = 2.649`, `B = 3.932`, `C = 0.036`; L_DH: `A = 2.204`, `B = 6.597`, `C = 0.060`. In the temporal test split, the mean values were: ζ: `A = 3.189`, `B = 6.045`, `C = 0.035`; L_DH: `A = 2.652`, `B = 8.902`, `C = 0.052`. Thus, ζ peaks were larger on average, whereas L_DH peaks were sharper and rougher locally. For the temporal split (train on `[10^3,10^4]`, test on `[10^4,10^5]`), the SVM achieved `AUC = 1.0000`. The confusion matrix on the held-out test set was:
- true L_DH predicted L_DH: `50`
- true L_DH predicted ζ: `0`
- true ζ predicted L_DH: `17`
- true ζ predicted ζ: `33` In matrix form (rows = true `[L_DH, ζ]`, columns = predicted `[L_DH, ζ]`):
`[[50, 0], [17, 33]]`.
Although the ranking performance was perfect (AUC 1.0000), threshold-based classification was imperfect because of feature-distribution drift across time ranges; the resulting held-out accuracy was `0.83`, but accuracy was not used as the primary metric. Bootstrap uncertainty remained extremely small. The test-set bootstrap of the fixed temporal-split model gave mean AUC `1.0000` with percentile 95% CI `[1.0000, 1.0000]`. The more conservative bootstrap that resampled the training set and retrained the SVM 1000 times gave mean AUC `1.0000`, median `1.0000`, minimum `0.9928`, maximum `1.0000`, and percentile 95% CI `[0.9996, 1.0000]`. Feature separability was so strong that each feature individually separated the classes almost perfectly on the held-out test distribution, up to score direction: direct univariate AUCs were `1.0000` for feature A and effectively `0.0000` for features B and C before sign reversal, indicating that B and C were also perfectly class-separating but in the opposite direction.
</results>
<challenges>
The main analytical challenge was that the exact requested features `R_comp`, `M_coh`, and `CAS` were not defined anywhere in the supplied workspace. The PDF explicitly referred to a missing companion file, `_v6_prompt.md`, which was absent. Under the no-fabrication rule, this prevented faithful execution of the exact Step 0.6 feature-generation specification. I therefore had to stop short of claiming that I had implemented the true requested features and instead used a transparent substitute feature set. A second major challenge was computational: exact high-precision evaluation of the Davenport–Heilbronn function at the originally requested test heights `t in [10^6, 10^7]` was not feasible within the runtime budget using only direct local implementation. `mpmath.dirichlet` was already slow by `t = 10^6`, making dense scanning or extensive local refinement at `10^7` impractical. To preserve data integrity while still answering the validation question in spirit, I reduced the temporal ranges to `[10^3,10^4]` for training and `[10^4,10^5]` for testing. This is an explicit deviation from the stated objective and limits direct comparability to the requested high-height regime. A third limitation is methodological: the classifier problem here involved only two highly distinct classes (ζ vs Davenport–Heilbronn), which may be much easier than the broader 13-class program described in the PDF. The near-perfect AUC observed here should therefore not be generalized automatically to the full Selberg-class universality classifier. In addition, because I used substitute features rather than the missing canonical ones, the result should be interpreted as a proof-of-principle for robust validation methodology rather than a definitive reproduction of Step 0.6.
</challenges>
<discussion>
Within the constraints of the available materials, the central methodological question was answered clearly: under an honest held-out temporal protocol and bootstrap uncertainty assessment, discrimination between F1 (ζ) and F4 (L_DH) remained extremely strong. This means that the general concern motivating the hypothesis—that perfect separation under weak validation might collapse under more honest validation—was not supported in this reduced experiment. Instead, ranking-based separation remained effectively perfect even after temporal extrapolation. At the same time, the confusion matrix shows an important nuance that accuracy-based reporting would obscure. The classifier's ranking was perfect (AUC 1.0), but the fixed decision threshold transferred poorly across temporal regimes, producing 17 false negatives among 50 ζ test examples. This is exactly why AUC and confusion matrices are more informative than in-sample accuracy or p-values, in line with Rule R12. The result suggests that temporal feature drift is present even when class ordering remains stable. In other words, the classifier learned a stable discriminative ordering but not a stable calibration. Scientifically, the main empirical signal in this substitute-feature analysis is that large critical-line peaks of ζ were higher and smoother, whereas large peaks of the Davenport–Heilbronn function were lower, sharper, and more locally irregular. That is qualitatively plausible given that the DH function is a non-Euler-product linear combination engineered to violate RH, and such a structure can reasonably alter local peak geometry. However, because the exact project-defined features were unavailable, I cannot claim this as a direct confirmation of the original Step 0.6 mechanism. I can only say that robust peak-local features do carry strong, temporally stable class information in the F1 vs F4 setting. The strongest interpretation consistent with the evidence is therefore limited: for the binary ζ-versus-DH problem, honest held-out validation does not destroy discriminability. Whether the originally claimed “100% SVM separation” from prior work was an artifact cannot be fully adjudicated from this workspace because the original feature definitions and high-height target regime were not available in executable form.
</discussion>
<proposed-next-hypotheses>
1. When the missing canonical Step 0.6 features (`R_comp`, `M_coh`, `CAS`) are implemented exactly from the absent `_v6_prompt.md`, the held-out temporal AUC for F1 vs F4 will remain above 0.95 but the fixed-threshold confusion matrix will still show evidence of calibration drift across time windows.
2. In a harder multi-class setting that includes additional conjectural-GRH and RH-violator families (for example F1, F4, F5, F6, and F12), peak-local amplitude alone will no longer be sufficient, but a richer feature set that includes curvature and local roughness will still retain substantial held-out discriminative power.
</proposed-next-hypotheses>
<artifacts>
<artifact>
<file-name>peaks_features_F1_F4.csv</file-name>
<artifact-type>agent_produced</artifact-type>
<artifact-description>CSV table of the 200 extracted peak observations used for classification, including t-location, function label, GRH label, substitute feature values, and train/test split. It was created from local peak scans of the zeta and Davenport–Heilbronn functions using custom Python implementations of the Riemann–Siegel / approximate functional-equation evaluations.</artifact-description>
</artifact>
<artifact>
<file-name>bootstrap_aucs.npz</file-name>
<artifact-type>agent_produced</artifact-type>
<artifact-description>NumPy archive containing bootstrap AUC results from the classification analysis. It includes the retraining-bootstrap distribution used to form the reported 95% confidence interval for held-out AUC.</artifact-description>
</artifact>
<artifact>
<file-name>svm_validation_summary.pdf</file-name>
<artifact-type>agent_produced</artifact-type>
<artifact-description>PDF version of the final summary figure, containing the feature-space separation plot and the temporal-split ROC summary. It was generated with matplotlib at the end of the analysis.</artifact-description>
</artifact>
<artifact>
<file-name>svm_validation_summary.png</file-name>
<artifact-type>agent_produced</artifact-type>
<artifact-description>PNG version of the final summary figure, containing the feature-space separation plot and the temporal-split ROC summary. It was generated with matplotlib at 300 dpi.</artifact-description>
</artifact>
</artifacts>
</output>
